He fought for freedom to defy an empire
Robert the Bruce is a drama, history film directed by Richard Gray.
In 1306, Scottish King Robert the Bruce turns a
defeated outlaw when his country is invaded.
But before to free his sacred land, he must manage to regain his will to fight back and
survive the persecution of those who want take his head and the English gold.
Robert the Bruce, played by Angus Macfadyen.
Morag, played by Anna Hutchison.
Brandubh, played by Zach McGowan.
Scot, played by Gabriel Bateman.
Iver, played by Talitha Eliana Bateman.
Carney, played by Brandon Lessard.
Robert the Bruce is a 2019 British epic historical fiction war film directed
by Richard Gray concerning the renowned king of the same name.
It is a spin-off/sequel to Mel Gibson's Braveheart (1995), with
Angus Macfadyen reprising his role as Robert the Bruce.
A character-driven ensemble piece, it portrays Robert's relationship with a peasant family as a
galvanising influence on his struggle for independence and his ensuing reign.
The film explores themes of scotland, family secrets,
king, 14th century, mother son relationship.
The tone is emotional.